<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Big Data on Oleg Baydakov</title>
    <link>https://obaydakov.github.io/categories/big-data/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Big Data on Oleg Baydakov</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 26 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://obaydakov.github.io/categories/big-data/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Adding Realtime Data Streaming To Your App</title>
      <link>https://obaydakov.github.io/post/2017/adding-realtime-data-streaming-to-your-app/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://obaydakov.github.io/post/2017/adding-realtime-data-streaming-to-your-app/</guid>
      <description>“[Realtime] is about the ability to make better decisions and take meaningful actions at the right time. It’s about detecting fraud while someone is swiping a credit card, or triggering an offer while a shopper is standing on a checkout line, or placing an ad on a website while someone is reading a specific article. It’s about combining and analyzing data so you can take the right action, at the right time, and at the right place.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Divolte Collector</title>
      <link>https://obaydakov.github.io/post/2017/divolte-collector/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://obaydakov.github.io/post/2017/divolte-collector/</guid>
      <description>Scalable clickstream collection for Hadoop and Kafka
Divolte Collector is a scalable and performant server for collecting clickstream data in HDFS and on Kafka topics. It uses a JavaScript tag on the client side to gather user interaction data, similar to many other web tracking solutions. Divolte Collector can be used as the foundation to build anything from basic web analytics dashboarding to real-time recommender engines or banner optimization systems.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hive MySQL Metastore and HiveServer2 Setup</title>
      <link>https://obaydakov.github.io/post/2017/hive-mysql-metastore-and-hiveserver2-setup/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://obaydakov.github.io/post/2017/hive-mysql-metastore-and-hiveserver2-setup/</guid>
      <description>By default, Hive comes with an embedded derby metastore; which stores the meta data and schema of Hive. However, it allows only one user in embedded mode. So it’s advisable to setup an external metastore. Below will be the architecture with MySQL as Metastore.
HiveServer2 – As you can see for JDBC/ODBC communication Hive has a thrift server – HiveServer2. This service is required to do CRUD (DML/DDL) from a script or program (e.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>