<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Weka on Oleg Baydakov</title>
    <link>https://obaydakov.github.io/tags/weka/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Weka on Oleg Baydakov</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 02 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://obaydakov.github.io/tags/weka/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Deep Feature Synthesis: Towards Automating Data Science Endeavors</title>
      <link>https://obaydakov.github.io/post/deep-feature-synthesis-towards-automating-data-science-endeavors/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://obaydakov.github.io/post/deep-feature-synthesis-towards-automating-data-science-endeavors/</guid>
      <description>Abstract-In this paper, we develop the Data Science Machine, which is able to derive predictive models from raw data automatically. To achieve this automation, we first propose and develop the Deep Feature Synthesis algorithm for automatically generating features for relational datasets. The algorithm follows relationships in the data to a base field, and then sequentially applies mathematical functions along that path to create the final feature. Second, we implement a generalizable machine learning pipeline and tune it using a novel Gaussian Copula process based approach.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Auto-WEKA 2.0: Automatic model selection and hyperparameter optimization in WEKA</title>
      <link>https://obaydakov.github.io/post/auto-weka-2-0-automatic-model-selection-and-hyperparameter-optimization-in-weka/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://obaydakov.github.io/post/auto-weka-2-0-automatic-model-selection-and-hyperparameter-optimization-in-weka/</guid>
      <description>WEKA is a widely used, open-source machine learning platform. Due to its intuitive interface, it is particularly popular with novice users. However, such users often find it hard to identify the best approach for their particular dataset among the many available. We describe the new version of Auto-WEKA, a system designed to help such users by automatically searching through the joint space of WEKA’s learning algorithms and their respective hyperparameter settings to maximize performance, using a state-of-the-art Bayesian optimization method.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>