<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blockchain on Oleg Baydakov</title>
    <link>https://obaydakov.github.io/categories/blockchain/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Blockchain on Oleg Baydakov</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 05 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://obaydakov.github.io/categories/blockchain/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Learn Blockchains by Building One</title>
      <link>https://obaydakov.github.io/post/2017/learn-blockchains-by-building-one/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://obaydakov.github.io/post/2017/learn-blockchains-by-building-one/</guid>
      <description>The fastest way to learn how Blockchains work is to build one
You’re here because, like me, you’re psyched about the rise of Cryptocurrencies. And you want to know how Blockchains work—the fundamental technology behind them. But understanding Blockchains isn’t easy—or at least wasn’t for me. I trudged through dense videos, followed porous tutorials, and dealt with the amplified frustration of too few examples.
I like learning by doing. It forces me to deal with the subject matter at a code level, which gets it sticking.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hadoop Crypto Ledger (hadoopcryptoledger)</title>
      <link>https://obaydakov.github.io/post/2017/hadoop-crypto-ledger-hadoopcryptoledger/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://obaydakov.github.io/post/2017/hadoop-crypto-ledger-hadoopcryptoledger/</guid>
      <description>This repository will provide various components to read crypto ledgers, such as the Bitcoin blockchain, with Hadoop and Ecosystem components, such as Flink, Spark, TEZ, Hive and MapReduce.
You find more information about the project in the Wiki.
Link</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>When do you need blockchain? Decision models.</title>
      <link>https://obaydakov.github.io/post/2017/when-do-you-need-blockchain-decision-models/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://obaydakov.github.io/post/2017/when-do-you-need-blockchain-decision-models/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blockchain Infrastructure Landscape: A First Principles Framing</title>
      <link>https://obaydakov.github.io/post/2017/blockchain-infrastructure-landscape-a-first-principles-framing/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://obaydakov.github.io/post/2017/blockchain-infrastructure-landscape-a-first-principles-framing/</guid>
      <description>How are Ethereum, IPFS/Filecoin, and BigchainDB complementary? What about Golem, Polkadot, or Interledger? I often get questions like this. So, I decided to write about how I answer those questions, via a first-principles framing.
The quick answer: there’s no one magic system called “blockchain” that magically does everything. Rather, there are really good building blocks of computing that can be used together to create effective decentralized applications. Ethereum can play a role, BigchainDB can play a role, and many more as well.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blockchains for Big Data</title>
      <link>https://obaydakov.github.io/post/2017/blockchains-for-big-data/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://obaydakov.github.io/post/2017/blockchains-for-big-data/</guid>
      <description>A New Tool For Big Data: Blockchain Technology
The recent surge in blockchain technology was sparked by Bitcoin. Technically, all blockchains are simply databases, but databases with “blue ocean” benefits: decentralized / shared control, immutability / audit trails, and native assets / exchanges.
By modern database standards, traditional blockchains have terrible scalability and don’t even have query languages; nonetheless, the blue ocean benefits were enough to capture the imagination of the globe.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Watson IoT Blockchain Sample Documentation</title>
      <link>https://obaydakov.github.io/post/2017/watson-iot-blockchain-sample-documentation/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://obaydakov.github.io/post/2017/watson-iot-blockchain-sample-documentation/</guid>
      <description>Introduction
Watson IoT blockchain samples currently fall into three broad categories:
 simple single-asset hello world sample
 simple single-asset sample with numerous additional features
 advanced multi-asset sample with events and additional features
  All of these use a schema to drive the related monitoring UI, which can be used to initiate any transaction or query that is exported for external use via the JSON configuration file.
Link</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>