<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>R on Oleg Baydakov</title>
    <link>https://obaydakov.github.io/categories/r/</link>
    <description>Recent content in R on Oleg Baydakov</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 28 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://obaydakov.github.io/categories/r/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Customer Analytics: Using Deep Learning With Keras To Predict Customer Churn</title>
      <link>https://obaydakov.github.io/post/customer-analytics-using-deep-learning-with-keras-to-predict-customer-churn/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://obaydakov.github.io/post/customer-analytics-using-deep-learning-with-keras-to-predict-customer-churn/</guid>
      <description>Customer churn is a problem that all companies need to monitor, especially those that depend on subscription-based revenue streams. The simple fact is that most organizations have data that can be used to target these individuals and to understand the key drivers of churn, and we now have Keras for Deep Learning available in R (Yes, in R!!), which predicted customer churn with 82% accuracy. We’re super excited for this article because we are using the new keras package to produce an Artificial Neural Network (ANN) model on the IBM Watson Telco Customer Churn Data Set!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Data Science for Fraud Detection</title>
      <link>https://obaydakov.github.io/post/data-science-for-fraud-detection/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://obaydakov.github.io/post/data-science-for-fraud-detection/</guid>
      <description>Fraud can be defined as “the crime of getting money by deceiving people” (Cambridge Dictionary); it is as old as humanity: whenever two parties exchange goods or conduct business, there is the potential for one party scamming the other. With an ever-increasing use of the internet for shopping, banking, filing insurance claims etc., these businesses have become targets of fraud in a whole new dimension. Fraud has become a major problem in e-commerce and a lot of resources are being invested to recognize and prevent it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Visualising Flows Using Network and Sankey Diagrams in Python and R</title>
      <link>https://obaydakov.github.io/post/visualising-flows-using-network-and-sankey-diagrams-in-python-and-r/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://obaydakov.github.io/post/visualising-flows-using-network-and-sankey-diagrams-in-python-and-r/</guid>
      <description>networkD3
Creating Alluvial Diagram</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>sparklyr: R interface for Apache Spark</title>
      <link>https://obaydakov.github.io/post/2017/sparklyr-r-interface-for-apache-spark/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://obaydakov.github.io/post/2017/sparklyr-r-interface-for-apache-spark/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Comparison of ML Classifiers Using Sparklyr</title>
      <link>https://obaydakov.github.io/post/2017/comparison-of-ml-classifiers-using-sparklyr/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://obaydakov.github.io/post/2017/comparison-of-ml-classifiers-using-sparklyr/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Explore Predictive Maintenance with flexdashboard</title>
      <link>https://obaydakov.github.io/post/2017/explore-predictive-maintenance-with-flexdashboard/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://obaydakov.github.io/post/2017/explore-predictive-maintenance-with-flexdashboard/</guid>
      <description>Predictive Maintenance is an increasingly popular strategy associated with Industry 4.0; it uses advanced analytics and machine learning to optimize machine costs and output (see Google Trends plot below).
A common use case for Predictive Maintenance is to proactively monitor machines, so as to predict when a check-up is needed to reduce failure and maximize performance. In contrast to traditional maintenance, where each machine has to undergo regular routine check-ups, Predictive Maintenance can save costs and reduce downtime.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Shine semantic package</title>
      <link>https://obaydakov.github.io/post/2017/shine-semantic-package/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://obaydakov.github.io/post/2017/shine-semantic-package/</guid>
      <description>Shiny.semantic
Semantic UI wrapper for Shiny
With this library it’s easy to wrap Shiny with Semantic UI components. Add a few simple lines of code and some CSS classes to give your UI a fresh, modern and highly interactive look.
Link
How we built a Shiny App for 700 users?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Awesome R</title>
      <link>https://obaydakov.github.io/post/2017/awesome-r/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://obaydakov.github.io/post/2017/awesome-r/</guid>
      <description>A curated list of awesome R frameworks, libraries and software.
Link</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Awesome R Shiny</title>
      <link>https://obaydakov.github.io/post/2017/awesome-r-shiny/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://obaydakov.github.io/post/2017/awesome-r-shiny/</guid>
      <description>A curated list of resources for R Shiny
Link</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Crosstalk</title>
      <link>https://obaydakov.github.io/post/2017/crosstalk/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://obaydakov.github.io/post/2017/crosstalk/</guid>
      <description>Crosstalk is an add-on to the htmlwidgets package. It extends htmlwidgets with a set of classes, functions, and conventions for implementing cross-widget interactions (currently, linked brushing and filtering).
Play with the example below by manipulating the slider, clicking rows in the data table, and playing with the selection button in the map.
Link</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Docker for Data Scientists</title>
      <link>https://obaydakov.github.io/post/2017/docker-for-data-scientists/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://obaydakov.github.io/post/2017/docker-for-data-scientists/</guid>
      <description>Data scientists inhabit such an ever-changing landscape of languages, packages, and frameworks that it can be easy to succumb to tool fatigue. If this sounds familiar, you may have missed the increasing popularity of Linux containers in the DevOps world, in particular Docker. Michelangelo D&amp;rsquo;Agostino demonstrates Docker&amp;rsquo;s many benefits, from making data science code and environments more portable and shareable to making the transition from development to production more seamless to giving data scientists a common basis for collaborating with software engineers, and explains why Docker deserves a place in every data scientist&amp;rsquo;s toolkit.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Random Bot for OpenML platform</title>
      <link>https://obaydakov.github.io/post/2017/random-bot-for-openml-platform/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://obaydakov.github.io/post/2017/random-bot-for-openml-platform/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lsquo;RandomBot&amp;rsquo; is a program that searches randomly the hyper-parameter space from different Machine Learning (ML) algorithms, sampling different hyper-parameter settings via hyper-parameter sweep. It executes pre-defined &amp;lsquo;mlr&amp;rsquo; [1] learners over OpenML [2] classification problems using the &amp;lsquo;BatchExperiments&amp;rsquo; package [3] structure.
For each pair of {task, algorithm}, the bot will start N new jobs with random different hper-parameter settings. The budget N is defined as N = 100 * D , where D denotes the number of parameters in that algorithm&amp;rsquo;s space, and 100 is the tuning constant (defined empirically).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Trelliscope</title>
      <link>https://obaydakov.github.io/post/2017/trelliscope/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://obaydakov.github.io/post/2017/trelliscope/</guid>
      <description>Trelliscope is a visualization approach based on the idea of &amp;ldquo;small multiples&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;Trellis Display&amp;rdquo;, where data are split into groups and a plot is made for each group, with the resulting plots arranged in a grid. This approach is very simple yet is considered to be &amp;ldquo;the best design solution for a wide range or problems in data presentation&amp;rdquo;. Trelliscope makes small multiple displays come alive by providing the ability to interactively sort and filter the plots based on summary statistics computed for each group.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Web Sites with R</title>
      <link>https://obaydakov.github.io/post/2017/web-sites-with-r/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://obaydakov.github.io/post/2017/web-sites-with-r/</guid>
      <description>Blogdown (R package)
blogdown ??? Hugo + R Markdown
Hugo can only process Markdown; R Markdown is prebuilt to .html and passed to Hugo a few helper functions
new_site() creates a new website
install_hugo() / install_theme()
serve_site() rebuilds and live reloads a website on changes (RStudio addin &amp;ldquo;Live Preview Site&amp;rdquo;)
new_post() creates a new post under content/post/ and automatically fills out some YAML metadata (title, author, date, &amp;hellip;)
output format: blogdown::html_page</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introduction to parallel computing with R</title>
      <link>https://obaydakov.github.io/post/2017/introduction-to-parallel-computing-with-r/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://obaydakov.github.io/post/2017/introduction-to-parallel-computing-with-r/</guid>
      <description>Link</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OpenML: Connecting R to the Machine Learning Platform OpenML</title>
      <link>https://obaydakov.github.io/post/2017/openml-connecting-r-to-the-machine-learning-platform-openml/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://obaydakov.github.io/post/2017/openml-connecting-r-to-the-machine-learning-platform-openml/</guid>
      <description>Tutorial 1
Tutorial 2
Slides
R interface to OpenML
Tutorial 3
Tutorial 4</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Package ggiraph: a ggplot2 Extension for Interactive Graphics</title>
      <link>https://obaydakov.github.io/post/2017/package-ggiraph-a-ggplot2-extension-for-interactive-graphics/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://obaydakov.github.io/post/2017/package-ggiraph-a-ggplot2-extension-for-interactive-graphics/</guid>
      <description>ggiraph is an htmlwidget and a ggplot2 extension. It lets ggplot graphics being animated.
Animation is made with ggplot geometries that can understand three arguments:
tooltip: column of dataset that contains tooltips to be displayed when mouse is over elements.
onclick: column of dataset that contains javascript function to be executed when elements are clicked.
data_id: column of dataset that contains id to be associated with elements.
Link
Video</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>jug: A Simple Web Framework for R</title>
      <link>https://obaydakov.github.io/post/2017/jug-a-simple-web-framework-for-r/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://obaydakov.github.io/post/2017/jug-a-simple-web-framework-for-r/</guid>
      <description>jug is a web framework aimed at easily building APIs. It is mostly aimed at exposing R functions, models and visualizations to third-parties by way of http requests.
Link
Video</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>shiny.semantic</title>
      <link>https://obaydakov.github.io/post/2017/shiny-semantic/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://obaydakov.github.io/post/2017/shiny-semantic/</guid>
      <description>Semantic UI wrapper for Shiny
With this library it&amp;rsquo;s easy to wrap Shiny with Semantic UI components. Add a few simple lines of code and some CSS classes to give your UI a fresh, modern and highly interactive look.
Link
Video</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>iheatmapr-  R package</title>
      <link>https://obaydakov.github.io/post/2017/iheatmapr-r-package/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://obaydakov.github.io/post/2017/iheatmapr-r-package/</guid>
      <description>iheatmapr is an R package for building complex, interactive heatmaps using modular building blocks. &amp;ldquo;Complex&amp;rdquo; heatmaps are heatmaps in which subplots along the rows or columns of the main heatmap add more information about each row or column. For example, a one column additional heatmap may indicate what group a particular row or column belongs to. Complex heatmaps may also include multiple side by side heatmaps which show different types of data for the same conditions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Formattable data frame</title>
      <link>https://obaydakov.github.io/post/2017/formattable-data-frame/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://obaydakov.github.io/post/2017/formattable-data-frame/</guid>
      <description>Formattable data frames are data frames to be rendered as HTML table with formatter functions applied, which resembles conditional formatting in Microsoft Excel.
Article
Link Github</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Deep Learning &amp; Parameter Tuning with MXnet, H2o Package in R</title>
      <link>https://obaydakov.github.io/post/2017/deep-learning-parameter-tuning-with-mxnet-h2o-package-in-r/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://obaydakov.github.io/post/2017/deep-learning-parameter-tuning-with-mxnet-h2o-package-in-r/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Deep Learning isn&amp;rsquo;t a recent discovery. The seeds were sown back in the 1950s when the first artificial neural network was created. Since then, progress has been rapid, with the structure of the neuron being &amp;ldquo;re-invented&amp;rdquo; artificially.
Computers and mobiles have now become powerful enough to identify objects from images.
Not just images, they can chat with you as well! Haven&amp;rsquo;t you tried Google&amp;rsquo;s Allo app ? That&amp;rsquo;s not all-they can drive, make supersonic calculations, and help businesses solve the most complicated problems (more users, revenue, etc).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Feature Engineering &#43; H2o Gradient Boosting (GBM) in R Scores 0.936</title>
      <link>https://obaydakov.github.io/post/2017/feature-engineering-h2o-gradient-boosting-gbm-in-r-scores-0-936/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://obaydakov.github.io/post/2017/feature-engineering-h2o-gradient-boosting-gbm-in-r-scores-0-936/</guid>
      <description>Load data and explore Data Pre-processing Dropped Features One Hot Encoding Feature Engineering Model Training  Link</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tutorial on XGBoost and Parameter Tuning in R</title>
      <link>https://obaydakov.github.io/post/2017/tutorial-on-xgboost-and-parameter-tuning-in-r/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://obaydakov.github.io/post/2017/tutorial-on-xgboost-and-parameter-tuning-in-r/</guid>
      <description>Table of Contents  What is XGBoost? Why is it so good? How does XGBoost work? Understanding XGBoost Tuning Parameters Practical - Tuning XGBoost using R  Link</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>