<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>R on Oleg Baydakov</title>
    <link>https://obaydakov.github.io/tags/r/</link>
    <description>Recent content in R on Oleg Baydakov</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 17 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://obaydakov.github.io/tags/r/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>My favourite R package for: summarising data</title>
      <link>https://obaydakov.github.io/post/2018/my-favourite-r-package-for-summarising-data/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://obaydakov.github.io/post/2018/my-favourite-r-package-for-summarising-data/</guid>
      <description>Link</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Deep Learning With Keras To Predict Customer Churn</title>
      <link>https://obaydakov.github.io/post/2018/deep-learning-with-keras-to-predict-customer-churn/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://obaydakov.github.io/post/2018/deep-learning-with-keras-to-predict-customer-churn/</guid>
      <description>Link
Link</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Keras for R (RStudio)</title>
      <link>https://obaydakov.github.io/post/2017/keras-for-r-rstudio/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://obaydakov.github.io/post/2017/keras-for-r-rstudio/</guid>
      <description>Keras for R - R Studio examples
keras: Deep Learning in R</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>cheatsheets ai</title>
      <link>https://obaydakov.github.io/post/2017/cheatsheets-ai/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://obaydakov.github.io/post/2017/cheatsheets-ai/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ensemble learning - model stacking</title>
      <link>https://obaydakov.github.io/post/2017/ensemble-learning-model-stacking/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://obaydakov.github.io/post/2017/ensemble-learning-model-stacking/</guid>
      <description>Introduction

Stacking (sometimes called &amp;ldquo;stacked generalization&amp;rdquo;) involves training a learning algorithm to combine the predictions of several other learning algorithms.
 First, all of the other algorithms are trained using the available data
 Then a combiner algorithm, the metalearner, is trained to make a final prediction using all the predictions of the other algorithms as additional inputs. If an arbitrary metalearning algorithm is used, then stacking can theoretically represent any of the ensemble techniques described in this article, although in practice, a single-layer logistic regression model is often used for metalearning.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MICE: Multivariate Imputation by Chained Equations</title>
      <link>https://obaydakov.github.io/post/mice-multivariate-imputation-by-chained-equations/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://obaydakov.github.io/post/mice-multivariate-imputation-by-chained-equations/</guid>
      <description>Capabilities of mice package
The mice package contains functions to
Inspect the missing data pattern Impute the missing data mm times, resulting in mm completed data sets Diagnose the quality of the imputed values Analyze each completed data set Pool the results of the repeated analyses Store and export the imputed data in various formats Generate simulated incomplete data Incorporate custom imputation methods Choose which cells to impute
Link
Handling Missing Data in R with mice</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>EVERYTHING ARTIFICIAL INTELLIGENCE</title>
      <link>https://obaydakov.github.io/post/2017/everything-artificial-intelligence/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://obaydakov.github.io/post/2017/everything-artificial-intelligence/</guid>
      <description>Link
H2O Auto ML
h2oai/h2o-tutorials
Ensembles: Stacking, Super Learner</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Awesome R</title>
      <link>https://obaydakov.github.io/post/2017/awesome-r/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://obaydakov.github.io/post/2017/awesome-r/</guid>
      <description>Awesome R
A curated list of awesome R packages and tools
Link</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>High Level Design of Analytical system based on R</title>
      <link>https://obaydakov.github.io/post/2017/high-level-design-of-analytical-system-based-on-r/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://obaydakov.github.io/post/2017/high-level-design-of-analytical-system-based-on-r/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Docker for Data Scientists</title>
      <link>https://obaydakov.github.io/post/2017/docker-for-data-scientists/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://obaydakov.github.io/post/2017/docker-for-data-scientists/</guid>
      <description>Data scientists inhabit such an ever-changing landscape of languages, packages, and frameworks that it can be easy to succumb to tool fatigue. If this sounds familiar, you may have missed the increasing popularity of Linux containers in the DevOps world, in particular Docker. Michelangelo D&amp;rsquo;Agostino demonstrates Docker&amp;rsquo;s many benefits, from making data science code and environments more portable and shareable to making the transition from development to production more seamless to giving data scientists a common basis for collaborating with software engineers, and explains why Docker deserves a place in every data scientist&amp;rsquo;s toolkit.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OpenML: Connecting R to the Machine Learning Platform OpenML</title>
      <link>https://obaydakov.github.io/post/2017/openml-connecting-r-to-the-machine-learning-platform-openml/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://obaydakov.github.io/post/2017/openml-connecting-r-to-the-machine-learning-platform-openml/</guid>
      <description>Tutorial 1
Tutorial 2
Slides
R interface to OpenML
Tutorial 3
Tutorial 4</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>iheatmapr-  R package</title>
      <link>https://obaydakov.github.io/post/2017/iheatmapr-r-package/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://obaydakov.github.io/post/2017/iheatmapr-r-package/</guid>
      <description>iheatmapr is an R package for building complex, interactive heatmaps using modular building blocks. &amp;ldquo;Complex&amp;rdquo; heatmaps are heatmaps in which subplots along the rows or columns of the main heatmap add more information about each row or column. For example, a one column additional heatmap may indicate what group a particular row or column belongs to. Complex heatmaps may also include multiple side by side heatmaps which show different types of data for the same conditions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CatBoost</title>
      <link>https://obaydakov.github.io/post/2017/catboost/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://obaydakov.github.io/post/2017/catboost/</guid>
      <description>CatBoost is a state-of-the-art open-source gradient boosting on decision trees library.
Developed by Yandex researchers and engineers, it is the successor of the MatrixNet algorithm that is widely used within the company for ranking tasks, forecasting and making recommendations. It is universal and can be applied across a wide range of areas and to a variety of problems.
Accurate: leads or ties competition on standard benchmarks Robust: reduces the need for extensive hyper-parameter tuning Easy-to-use: offers Python interfaces integrated with scikit, as well as R and command-line interfaces Practical: uses categorical features directly and scalably Extensible: allows specifying custom loss functions</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Credit Risk Prediction</title>
      <link>https://obaydakov.github.io/post/2017/credit-risk-prediction/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://obaydakov.github.io/post/2017/credit-risk-prediction/</guid>
      <description>Credit Risk Scoring is a classic yet still increasingly important operation in banking as banks continue to be increasingly risk careful when lending for mortgages or commercial purposes, in an industry known for fierce competition and the global financial crisis. With an accurate credit risk scoring model a bank is able to predict the likelihood of default on a transaction. This will in turn help evaluate the potential risk posed by lending money to consumers and to mitigate losses due to bad debt, as well as determine who qualifies for a loan, at what interest rate, and what credit limits, and even determine which customers are likely to bring in the most revenue through a variety of products.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>R package MLR examples</title>
      <link>https://obaydakov.github.io/post/2017/r-package-mlr-examples/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://obaydakov.github.io/post/2017/r-package-mlr-examples/</guid>
      <description>Link</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introduction to Local Interpretable Model-Agnostic Explanations (LIME)</title>
      <link>https://obaydakov.github.io/post/2017/introduction-to-local-interpretable-model-agnostic-explanations-lime/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://obaydakov.github.io/post/2017/introduction-to-local-interpretable-model-agnostic-explanations-lime/</guid>
      <description>Machine learning is at the core of many recent advances in science and technology. With computers beating professionals in games like Go, many people have started asking if machines would also make for better drivers or even better doctors.
In many applications of machine learning, users are asked to trust a model to help them make decisions. A doctor will certainly not operate on a patient simply because &amp;ldquo;the model said so.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introduction to Local Interpretable Model-Agnostic Explanations (LIME)</title>
      <link>https://obaydakov.github.io/post/2017/introduction-to-local-interpretable-model-agnostic-explanations-lime/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://obaydakov.github.io/post/2017/introduction-to-local-interpretable-model-agnostic-explanations-lime/</guid>
      <description>Machine learning is at the core of many recent advances in science and technology. With computers beating professionals in games like Go, many people have started asking if machines would also make for better drivers or even better doctors.
In many applications of machine learning, users are asked to trust a model to help them make decisions. A doctor will certainly not operate on a patient simply because &amp;quot;the model said so.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Real-World Machine Learning (with R)</title>
      <link>https://obaydakov.github.io/post/2017/real-world-machine-learning-with-r/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://obaydakov.github.io/post/2017/real-world-machine-learning-with-r/</guid>
      <description>Introduction to rwml-R The book &amp;ldquo;Real-World Machine Learning&amp;rdquo; by Henrik Brink, Joseph W. Richards, and Mark Fetherolf attempts to prepare the reader for the realities of machine learning. It covers a basic framework for machine-learning projects, then it dives into extended examples that show how that basic framework can be applied in realistic situations. It attempts to provide the &amp;ldquo;hidden wisdom&amp;rdquo; on how to go about implementing products and solutions based on machine learning.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Algorithms and Data Structures</title>
      <link>https://obaydakov.github.io/post/2017/algorithms-and-data-structures/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://obaydakov.github.io/post/2017/algorithms-and-data-structures/</guid>
      <description>Algorithms and Data Structures
This is the collection of algorithms, data structures and Interview Questions with solutions. This repository contains my solutions for common algorithmic problems and implementation of Data Structures in Java. I&amp;rsquo;ve created this repository to learn about algorithms. I am adding solutions continuously. Link</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Use t-SNE Effectively</title>
      <link>https://obaydakov.github.io/post/2017/how-to-use-t-sne-effectively/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://obaydakov.github.io/post/2017/how-to-use-t-sne-effectively/</guid>
      <description>A popular method for exploring high-dimensional data is something called t-SNE, introduced by van der Maaten and Hinton in 2008 [1]. The technique has become widespread in the field of machine learning, since it has an almost magical ability to create compelling two-dimensonal &amp;ldquo;maps&amp;rdquo; from data with hundreds or even thousands of dimensions.
Useful links:
 How to Use t-SNE Effectively
 Dissect t-SNE
 Dimensionality reduction: PCA, MDS, t-SNE</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using TensorFlow with R</title>
      <link>https://obaydakov.github.io/post/2017/using-tensorflow-with-r/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://obaydakov.github.io/post/2017/using-tensorflow-with-r/</guid>
      <description>TensorFlowT is an open source software library for numerical computation using data flow graphs. Nodes in the graph represent mathematical operations, while the graph edges represent the multidimensional data arrays (tensors) communicated between them. The flexible architecture allows you to deploy computation to one or more CPUs or GPUs in a desktop, server, or mobile device with a single API. TensorFlow was originally developed by researchers and engineers working on the Google Brain Team within Google&amp;rsquo;s Machine Intelligence research organization for the purposes of conducting machine learning and deep neural networks research, but the system is general enough to be applicable in a wide variety of other domains as well.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>